Previously on Transformers Prime:
在上一集中
Simply put, this combination of elements could allow us to cyberform entire worlds.
简单地说 这种化合物可以让我们数字化整个世界
Then we will focus upon the successful reconstruction of the Omega Lock.
那我们就先集中手头的所有资源 全力修复终极之锁吧
Prime! It's 'Cons again.
擎天柱！虎子又露头了
In progress this time.
而且被我们抓了个正着
Ratchet, We will be returning with a Decepticon prisoner.
救护车 我们要带回一个霸天虎俘虏
Why is Megatron stealing human technology?
威震天为何要窃取人类科技？
What is he attempting to build?
他究竟想要建造什么？
Knock out first procured this unfinished shamble from the Autobot medic.
击倒从汽车人的医生哪里获取了这个未完成配方
The most efficient means to an end may be to recruit that medic.
那么最快的解决办法 就是将那名医生弄到手
It took a cataclysm to extinguish Cybertron's original Predacon inhabitants.
只有大灾变才能毁灭塞博特恩上的巨狰狞种族
You never stood a chance against me, Prime.
而你根本就不是我的对手 擎天柱
In fact, the time has come for your extinction.
事实上 今天你大限到了！
Permission to hasten our progress, chief?
头儿 可否速战速决？
Granted.
批准
This is no place for a one-handed Autobot.
这场战斗可不适合仅有一只手的汽车人
I'll take one bum hand over one good eye any day.
一只破手换一只好眼 这买卖划算
Stand down, Predacon.
收手吧 巨狰狞！
I am Predaking
我是冲云霄！
And I will never bow to your kind!
而我永远不会向你们屈服！
Predaking, I have been informed that our objective is at risk.
冲云霄 我得知我们的目标正受到威胁
Secure it. Now.
去保护它 快！
Commander, objective secured.
指挥官 目标已安全
Now might be a fine time for surrender.
现在是你投降的好机会
A logical assumption, were it not for...
根据逻辑推断 若不是…
Ah... aah!
啊…呀！
Ratchet, we require immediate transport back to base.
救护车 立即接我们回基地
Huh?
嗯？
Stewardess, there's a man on the wing of this plane!
空姐 有个家伙正站在我们飞机的翅膀上！
Ratchet, do you read?
救护车 你听到了吗？
Uh... Arcee...?
呃…阿尔茜？
Bulkhead?
隔板
Is everything all right?
一切都好吧？
Where's Ratchet?
救护车他人呢？
He's... he's gone.
他…他被掳走了…
What do you want from me?
你想从我这儿得到什么？
Your assistance, actually.
事实上 我需要你的协助
To help complete a little... science project.
来帮我们完成一个小…科研项目
I will never cooperate.
我绝不会合作的
Shockwave does not require your cooperation
震荡波可不需要你的合作…
to siphon your knowledge, doctor.
来汲取你脑中的知识 医生
Peeled some paint off Laserbeak.
只打掉激光鸟的一点喷漆而已
But if I were a better shot, Ratchet would still be here.
假如我枪法再好点 救护车就不会被劫走了
Chin up, soldier. We've combed the entire floor.
不要气馁 士兵 我们已经检查了整层楼
For the moment, that remains our only clue.
到目前为止 那是我们找到的唯一线索
Nothing in the groundbridge log.
环陆桥记录也毫无用处
If they bridged Ratchet out of here,
虽然他们是用环陆桥将人带走的
They used theirs, not ours.
但那是他们的桥 而不是我们的
Why take Ratchet prisoner, but leave these two behind?
为什么只抓走了救护车 而对他们俩置之不理？
If Megatron intends to hold our medic hostage,
如果威震天想将我们的医生掳为人质
I find it curious that he's made no demands.
我很奇怪他竟然没有提赎金
It would stand to reason that Ratchet must possess something the Decepticons want.
我们有理由相信 救护车手中应该有某种霸天虎想要的东西
Well, whatever the 'Cons are after, Ratch won't give it up.
无论虎子们想要什么 老救是不会给他们的
Right?
对吧？
Lord Megatron,
威震天陛下
I understand that you have brought an accursed Autobot aboard this warship.
我听说您将一个该死的汽车人带到了这艘战舰上
Indeed.
确实如此
Then I will accomplish with him what I failed to with the Prime.
那么我和擎天柱没算完的账 就用他结吧
Predaking, this Autobot is more than a prisoner.
冲云霄 这名汽车人可不只是俘虏
You do wish for Cybertron's restoration, do you not?
你难道不想修复塞博特恩了么？
Our captive's usefulness will come to an end.
不过他的价值终会消失
And when that time arrives, I assure you,
等到那个时候 我向你保证
he will be all yours.
他将任由你处置
Listen, I need 24/7 satellite monitoring.
听着 我需要全天候卫星监控
Eyes on the skies and ears to the ground!
无论是天上飞的 还是地上跑的 都给我盯紧了！
Maybe buckethead's after the techno-babble.
或许铁桶头想得到某个技术玩意
The synth-en formula?
合成能量的配方？
Why would the 'Cons need the artificial stuff If they already control most of this planet's energon reserves?
虎子已控制了这星球上几乎所有的能量 还要合成的玩意儿干什么？
Greed, what else?
还能为啥 贪婪呗
If Megatron is truly rebuilding the Omega Lock,
如果威震天真的如救护车推测的那样
As Ratchet surmised,
在试图重铸终极之锁
Synthetic energon might be a necessary component.
那么合成能量可能是一种不可或缺的原料
I hate to be the one to bring lightning to a thunderstorm,
我不想火上浇油
But there's one thing we're all ignoring.
但有一件事你们全都忽略了！
If the 'Cons found Ratchet here, they know the location of this base.
如果虎子们在这里抓走了救护车 那么他们已经知道了这个基地的位置
And what did the cortical psychic patch yield?
那么 大脑神经接入器获取了什么信息？
Only confirmation that the synthetic energon formula Is unstable,
只确认了合成能量的配方确实不稳定
and that the Autobot medic's work on it remains incomplete.
并且 汽车人医生对此项目的研究还未完成
Then it seems we must help Ratchet finish his work.
看来我们必须帮助救护车完成他的研究
Are you through poking around inside my head?
你在我的脑袋里折腾够了么？
You didn't find what you wanted, did you?
没找到你想要的东西 是吧？
Or else you wouldn't be here.
否则你也不会露面了
What I want apparently does not yet exist.
很明显 我想要的东西目前还不存在
And that would be...?
那东西是…？
We would very much like for you to complete your work on the formula for synthetic energon.
我们非常期待你能完成合成能量配方的研究
Even if I were capable, do you think that I would hand you a limitless supply of fuel and ammunition just
就算我能做到 但你觉得我会把用之不竭的能量和弹药拱手相送
so you can turn around and use it against the Autobots?
让你拿去对付汽车人吗？
Oh, you misunderstand, dearest Ratchet.
哦 你完全误会我们了 亲爱的救护车
I intend to use your formula for the purpose of creation,
我将把这个配方用于创造
Not destruction.
而非毁灭
We have fortuitously discovered that your synth-en, when combined with cyber-nucleic acid,
我们偶然发现 将你的合成能量与C.N.A.融合
May in fact form the basis for an alternative cyber-matter.
是制造一种塞博特恩网状物替代品的基础
You are attempting to rebuild the Omega Lock.
你果然是想重铸终极之锁
We stand on the verge of a great moment in time, you and I.
只要你我二人向前迈一小步 就可以创造历史的伟大一刻
The restoration of our very homeworld.
复苏我们的家园
Collaborate with the barbarian who essentially destroyed our planet in the first place?
通过与你合作？那个毁灭我们家园的罪魁祸首？
Who sadistically crushed Bumblebee's voice box while looking him in the eye?
那个面对面残忍地摧毁了大黄蜂发声器的野蛮人？
No, thank you.
不 谢谢了
Then I present you with a choice:
那么你就要做出选择了
Complete your research, or...
或者完成你的研究 或者…
Heh... humans, always the weak link.
哼哼哼 人类永远是你们的弱点
Are these humans supposed to mean something to me?
你觉得这些人类对我很重要么？
If not, I am certain this will.
如果他们不重要的话 我肯定这很重要
As you must certainly be aware,
你一定很清楚
We know the location of your current base.
我们已经掌握了你们基地的位置
Accept my offer, and I will allow your fellow Autobots and human pets to remain unharmed.
乖乖与我合作 我保证你的汽车人同伙和人类宠物会安然无恙
Think it over, good doctor.
好好考虑吧 善良的医生
My liege, you aren't really going to allow the Autobots to remain operational?
我的君王 您不会真的放过那些汽车人吧？
Of course not.
当然不会
Assemble your armada, Starscream,
立刻召集你的部队 红蜘蛛
And decimate their base once again.
去再次摧毁他们的基地吧
All aerial search patterns are coming up empty.
唉 所有空中搜索模式都一无所获
No comm-link chatter either.
也未拦截到虎子的任何通讯
And no ground activity.
也没有任何地面活动
It's a little too quiet out there.
虎子们安静得有点过了
Since the Decepticons no longer seek Predacon bones or Earth technology,
鉴于霸天虎已不再搜索巨狰狞骸骨或地球科技
there is no activity to track.
我们已无法追踪任何东西了
So until Megatron makes a move, we're in a holding pattern.
那么在威震天有所行动之前 我们只能静观其变了
Ratchet didn't think this new hand he built for me was good enough.
救护车觉得他为我造的这只新手并不够好
But I'll tell you what truly isn't good enough:
但我告诉你们什么才是真正的不够好
Giving up.
那就是放弃
We have no choice but to play this old school,
我们已别无选择 只能使用一些老办法了
Split into teams, for maximum coverage.
分散成小队搜索 尽可能覆盖最大的范围
We have incoming. A whole fleet's worth.
敌军来袭！是一整支舰队！
Concentrate your fire on hangar E.
集中火力打E机库
Air cover's holding. For the moment.
空军正在抵挡他们 但只是暂时的
Lord Megatron, I am pleased to report
威震天陛下 我非常高兴地向您汇报
that the Autobot base has been reduced to ashes.
汽车人的基地已被夷为平地了
The mess hall sure is a mess.
食堂这下成了“屎堂”
We are fortunate that Decepticons can be fooled by a simple paint job.
我们很幸运 仅靠简单的伪装就骗过了霸天虎
I'm sure you would more fully appreciate a tour of our facilities if you were comfortable.
我觉得让你放开手脚 你才有心情去参观我们的设施
How do you know I won't use these to amputate?
你怎么知道我不会用这些给自己截肢
And pass up a chance to see our molecular masking field?
那你可就没机会欣赏我们的分子伪装力场了
Your cloaking device.
你的隐形装置
Shielding is shielding, high tech or low.
不过一个力场而已 没什么技术含量
Perhaps you'll be more impressed by our energon transfusion capacitor.
或许我们的能量注入电容器能让你刮目相看呢？
It allows us to maximize our Consumption a thousand-fold.
它可以让我们的能量消耗上限扩大一千倍
Decepticon engineering never fails to impress.
霸天虎的工程科技 确实令人刮目相看
Doctor, we may be mortal enemies,
医生 虽然我们是死敌
But Autobots and Decepticons do share one common goal.
但汽车人与霸天虎却有一个共同的目标
You would like to see the ruins of our devastated homeworld restored to their former brilliance,
你们应该期盼我们被毁灭的家园恢复昔日的辉煌吧？
As would I.
而我也一样
Megatron, you would just try to conquer Cybertron All over again,
威震天 你不过是想再次征服塞博特恩
And enslave anyone who refuses to pledge allegiance to you.
并奴役所有拒绝效忠你的人
Of course I would!
我当然会那么做！
And your comrades would attempt to stop me, as ever.
而你的战友将会一如既往地尝试阻止我
But at least we would once again possess a planet worth fighting over.
但至少 我们再次拥有了一颗可以为之战斗的星球
Perhaps, but you wouldn't stop there, would you?
或许吧 但你不会满足于此的 是吧？
Earth would be next, if not first.
地球是你的第二个目标 或者是第一个
What assurance do I have that you would leave humankind be?
我如何确定你不会对人类下手
And that you wouldn't instantly terminate me once you get what you need?
并在你得到想要的东西后将我卸磨杀驴？
None whatsoever.
完全没法确定
After all, we both know that as a Decepticon,
毕竟你我都心知肚明
any assurances I might offer would be worthless.
我们霸天虎的承诺一钱不值
But that does not change the fact that you may be Cybertron's only hope of ever seeing life again.
但你或许是塞博特恩重见天日的唯一希望
So the kid clipped the business end of Laserbeak's transponder.
这么说 这小子打下了激光鸟应答器的功能终端
You're not such a bad shot after all.
看来你的枪法还是不错的
We thought you might be the best one to provide an analysis,
我们就知道 老救不在 你就是分析情报的最佳人选
It's trying to communicate with the warship.
它正在尝试与霸天虎战舰进行通讯
How do you know?
你怎么知道的？
It's telling us.
它正在告诉我们
Uh, Raf, that's Cybertronian code.
嗯 拉夫 那是塞博特恩代码
Wait, first Raf understands Bumblebee,
等等 拉夫先是能听懂大黄蜂说话
Now he reads Cybertronian?
现在又能看懂塞博特恩文字？
Are we sure he's not some kind of alien?
我们确定他不是一个外星人么？
I've been learning for a while, in between stuff
我已经断断续续学了一段时间了
when Ratchet had time to teach me.
救护车有空时 就会教我一些
Hey, Raf, we'll bring him back.
嘿 拉夫 我们会把他救回来的
If it's the last thing we do.
哪怕拼上性命
If it's talking to its momma can we triangulate the signal?
如果它正在和它的老妈聊天 我们能否追踪这个信号？
To a shielded warship?
追踪一艘被护盾保护着的战舰？
If the transponder were still attached to Laserbeak, We could follow it.
如果这个应答器仍在激光鸟身上 我们就可以跟踪它
Maybe we should give it wings.
或许我们该给它装副翅膀
We can use spare parts from the machine shop.
我们可以使用加工车间的零配件
Then let's do it, for the doc.
那么咱们开工吧 为了大夫
While your forces have put a dent in our resources,
当你千方百计地夺取我们的资源时
Shockwave has been invaluable in updating our laboratory.
震荡波一直在努力升级我们的实验室
Should you choose to accept the task,
如果你答应合作
You shall have unrestricted access to our equipment.
你将可以不受限制地使用我们的设备
Is that a quantum cryo-inducer?
这居然是量子低温诱导器？
Only two were ever made.
这东西只建造过两台
Three, actually.
事实上 是三台
You are holding the original prototype.
你手中的是最初的原型机
The frequency modulator keeps shorting out!
频率调节器总是短路！
Easy, champ. Let me try uncrossing some wires.
放松点 孩子 我去检查一下电线
Now there's something you don't see every day.
这情景可真少见
Ie wasn't always a loner, you know.
老千从前并不是个独行侠
Being a Wrecker was all about the team.
作为雷霆救援队员 队伍永远是第一位的
Yip-ip-ip-ip!
别 别 别！
Miko! I needed that!
神子！那个我还有用呐！
I was just trying to tighten up that thingamajig.
我只是想弄紧那个什么玩意
Pfff! Please!
切！拉倒吧！
Agent fowler.
福勒探员
Everything all right?
你没事吧？
Just preoccupied.
就是有点心事
Thinking about the close calls We humans have had with the 'Cons lately.
我在想最近我们从虎子手中死里逃生的情景
Smacked down by Soundwave, stuck in Knock out's trunk with your mom.
被声波打倒在地 和你妈妈一起被关在击倒的后备箱里
Moving on...
这个就甭提了
the uncomfortable reality is,
让人忧心的是
The 'bots might not always be here.
汽车人不会一直留在这里
And even if they are, they can't be everywhere at once,
即使他们在 他们也不能同时出现在所有地方
as we've learned.
我们已经有过教训
This armor is the only thing that stood between Miko and that Predacon.
这副盔甲是当时唯一能保护神子免遭巨狰狞毒手的东西
The reason she came back without a scratch.
正是因为它 神子才能毫发无伤
Cyber-tech like that could be just what we need
这类塞博特恩科技可能正是我们需要的
To give our agents on the front lines a fighting chance.
使我们前线的探员 在面对强敌时获得一线生机
Agents like, maybe you someday.
将来 你也很可能成为其中的一员
What?!
我？！
You'll be of age soon, and you're Prime material, son.
你很快就够年龄了 而且你是个领袖坯子 孩子
Your mom thought you might be a good fit,
你妈妈觉得你很适合这项工作
seeing as you've been wishy-washy about future plans.
鉴于你目前对自己的未来毫无打算
Wait, you've been talking to my mom? About me?
等等 你经常和我妈妈聊天？聊我的事？
Custer's mustache!
卡斯特的胡子！
Sorry, Agent Fowler.
抱歉 福勒探员
I think I need to change my star-spangled shorts.
看来我得换条星条旗短裤了
I'm still fine-tuning chip's remote.
我仍在调校芯片的遥控功能
Chip?
芯片？
So we're gonna let this doohickey fly back to 'con central...
也就是说 我们要让这个小玩意飞回虎子的指挥中心
And lead us right to Ratchet.
并给我们指明救护车的位置
Even if you manage to reconstruct the Omega Lock,
即使你能重铸终极之锁
It is a mystic force. I've come to my senses.
但很久以前我就意识到 它是一种神秘的力量
The notion of scientifically replicating its capability Is pure folly.
使用技术复制其能力是完全不可能的
Madness, even.
甚至可以称为痴心妄想！
But how will we ever know for certain, doctor... if we do not try?
但医生 如果我们不去尝试 如何确定这不可行呢？
And how can we not try, When the means finally lie within our reach?
而当万事俱备之际 我们何不放手一试呢？
By the Allspark,
火种源在上
you've actually done it.
你真的成功了
Decepticon engineering.
拜霸天虎工程技术所赐
It will not take long for this Omega Lock's drives to be fully operational.
用不了多久 终极之锁就可以全力运作了
All that is still needed to restore our home
那么复苏我们家园所唯一欠缺的
is the cyber-matter to launch through it.
就是它所产生的塞博特恩网状物
Which requires a stabilized formula for the production of synthetic energon.
这需要一个稳定的配方来生产合成能量
I have every confidence in you, doctor.
我对你完全有信心 医生
I'll do it.
我答应你
But then you already knew that, didn't you?
而这早就在你的预料之中 是不是？